<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Github | Linux Follower Log]]></title>
  <link href="http://jightuse.github.io/blog/categories/github/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://jightuse.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2014-01-11T04:56:40+07:00</updated>
  <id>http://jightuse.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Boris Egorov]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Octocat and a Bit of Rust]]></title>
    <link href="http://jightuse.github.io/blog/2014/01/11/octocat-and-a-bit-of-rust/"/>
    <updated>2014-01-11T03:17:13+07:00</updated>
    <id>http://jightuse.github.io/blog/2014/01/11/octocat-and-a-bit-of-rust</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>After month of waiting<sup id="fnref:1"><a href="#fn:1" rel="footnote">1</a></sup> I have finally received package from GitHub Shop with
a bunch of Octocat stickers. Stuck one on my notebook, one on my front door and
give a few to a friends. Pretty cute little things. Definitely, Github has gained
so much popularity thanks to mascot.</p>

<p><img class="<a" src="href="http://i.imgur.com/BhM910y.jpg">http://i.imgur.com/BhM910y.jpg</a>" width="520" height="390" title="&lsquo;Octocats&rsquo; &lsquo;Octocat stickers&rsquo;" ></p>

<p>Now for the code. As you may know, recently <a href="http://www.rust-lang.org/">Rust 0.9 had released</a>.
Today I was updating code in my small
<a href="https://github.com/JIghtuse/rosetta">rosetta</a> repo (solutions for
<a href="http://rosettacode.org/">rosettacode</a>) and discover one funny easter egg.</p>

<p>Here is a program for finding the limit of recursion in Rust 0.9 (version for
Rust 0.8 differs only by printing line).
``` rust
fn recurse(n: int) {</p>

<pre><code>println!("deep: {:d}", n);
recurse(n + 1);
</code></pre>

<p>}</p>

<p>fn main() {</p>

<pre><code>recurse(0);
</code></pre>

<p>}
<code>
This code has failing with segfault in Rust 0.8 printing last line `deep: 7892`.
Now it aborts on some assertion giving this great message:
</code> xml
deep: 12952</p>

<p>There are not many persons who know what wonders are opened to them in the
stories and visions of their youth; for when as children we listen and dream,
we think but half-formed thoughts, and when as men we try to remember, we are
dulled and prosaic with the poison of life. But some of us awake in the night
with strange phantasms of enchanted hills and gardens, of fountains that sing
in the sun, of golden cliffs overhanging murmuring seas, of plains that stretch
down to sleeping cities of bronze and stone, and of shadowy companies of heroes
that ride caparisoned white horses along the edges of thick forests; and then
we know that we have looked back through the ivory gates into that world of
wonder which was ours before we were wise and unhappy.</p>

<p>fatal runtime error:  assertion failed: !ptr.is_null()
Aborted
```</p>

<p>Folks from <a href="http://chat.mibbit.com/?server=irc.mozilla.org&amp;channel=%23rust">#rust on irc.mozilla.org</a>
said that theoretically this code must print something like
<code>task '&lt;main&gt;' has overflowed its stack</code>, but overflow probably occurs in
println statement, so we have this nice Lovecraft quote instead.</p>
<div class="footnotes">
<hr/>
<ol>
<li id="fn:1">
<p>Russian Post especially cool on holidays.<a href="#fnref:1" rev="footnote">&#8617;</a></p></li>
</ol>
</div>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
